lendup.com 2016-08-17

# Privacy & Security

## LendUp Privacy Policy

LendUp is dedicated to promoting a world of transparency & complete disclosure in the financial services industry.

We take our customer privacy very seriously and are committed to our customers' privacy. Scroll down this page to learn what personal information we collect from consumers, how we collect and use it, how we protect it, and how we share personal information. We do not share our customers’ or former customers’ personal information except for our everyday business purposes such as to verify identity or eligibility for our loan products, to process transactions, maintain account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus. 

## What types of personal information we collect, how we collect it, and how we use it.

LendUp collects two types of information to create the best customer experience: (1) Personal information that users like you submit to LendUp via our website, and (2) Website usage information that is automatically generated by users as they interact with the site or information that we access via application programming interfaces.

### 1\. Personal Information

LendUp uses personal information as required by state and federal regulators to assure we are promoting safe and responsible lending.

When you first apply for a loan via the LendUp website (www.lendup.com), we ask you to create an account and then ask you to supply certain personal information. We use this information:

  * to verify (as much as reasonably possible) that it is you, rather than someone else, that is applying for the loan in your name
  * to determine your eligibility for the requested loan under the law and whether you can afford it
  * to maintain your account
  * to communicate with you about your account
  * to securely process the funding and repayment transactions to which you and we might agree

The types of personal information we collect for these purposes can include: 

  * basic profile information such as your name, address, phone number, email address, preferences, and other similar information
  * identifying information such as social security number, date of birth, or other information
  * information such as employment, income or similar information 
  * transactional information such as including bank account numbers, routing numbers, debit card numbers or similar information

**COLLECTION AND USE OF BANK ACCOUNT INFORMATION:** As part of our application process, we require banking information. In processing your application, we may detect additional bank accounts under your ownership. We will consider these additional accounts to be part of the application process. By applying, you authorize us to search for and evaluate bank accounts under your ownership for this purpose.

LendUp may also obtain more information about applicants from third parties to help us validate this information. We also collect tokens from online services and payment systems.

After you become a LendUp customer by obtaining a loan we provide via our website, we use your information for transaction processing and to communicate with you.

### 2\. Website Usage Information

LendUp uses "website usage" information to help create a better user experience.

LendUp collects certain information from users' browsers using small text files called "cookies." LendUp uses session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in. This type of cookie helps LendUp recognize a user if he or she visits multiple pages on our site during the same session, so that we do not need to require a password to access each page. Please note: If you do not accept cookies from LendUp, you will not be able to use our site.

We also use a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you come back to LendUp on future visits. We encode our cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them, but they do not contain personally identifiable information. Users can remove or block the persistent cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable the feature.

LendUp also stores transaction history and user relationships/interactions. We collect this information so that we can provide users with a meaningful service.

LendUp may collect additional information in other ways not specifically described here. For example, we may collect information related to interactions with customer services, collections, surveys or other feedback tools from third parties using technologies such as application programming interfaces (APIs).

LendUp's primary purpose in collecting personal information during website usage is to provide users with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience and allow them to take full advantage of our products and services.

LendUp uses this information to provide services and support; process transactions and send notifications regarding general operation of the service, such as messages or reminders, resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems; prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our user agreement; customize, measure, and improve our services and the content and layout of our website; compare information for accuracy and verify it with third parties.

## How we protect users’ personal information

#### LendUp Protects Your Information With The Latest Internet Technology.

LendUp collects and stores certain information in order to provide the best solutions for our customers, today and tomorrow. We strive to go beyond industry standards to make sure your information is safe and secure, and we restrict access to protect you against fraud.

When you enter personally identifiable information on our registration page we use a 128-bit secure socket layer (SSL).

LendUp uses computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, and authorizes access to personal information only for those employees who require it to fulfill their job responsibilities. Our data is encrypted before, during and after it is submitted to have the best protection of your information. Only authorized employees can access the data and they must submit multiple forms of identity verification before accessing any information.

LendUp does not store payment or related personal data at our offices.

Instead of storing payment information on company systems, LendUp stores this information in PCI DSS Level 1 certified secure data centers located only in the United States. This information is protected by physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in compliance with applicable US federal and state regulations. Our data is stored in a physically protected environment. Physical access is strictly controlled.

LendUp encrypts and securely transmits user payment information to the banking network at the time of initial payment acceptance. LendUp receives the response along with a "payment token" that it uses to reference that transaction for any future billing action. LendUp stores only this secure token.

#### LendUp Does Not Intentionally Share Your Information

LendUp does not share a user's personal or financial information with other customers or users. It is your responsibility to protect your account access codes, including your username and password, so others can’t access your account.

#### LendUp Does Not Sell Your Personal Information To Third Parties

LendUp takes your privacy seriously and does not sell your personal information to third parties.

LendUp may share personal information with partners under contract who help with certain parts of our business operations including application evaluation, customer services, payment, fraud prevention, secure data storage, collections and other similar services.

Regarding Texas customer information, LendUp may share your personal information with the lender with which you apply for a loan or from which you obtain a loan via our website using our credit services. You can find such lender’s privacy policy via hyperlinks on our Consumer Disclosures for CAB Credit Services web page or hyperlinks on your loan agreement.

LendUp will only use personal information in connection with the services LendUp provides. LendUp may share personal information in the event of a merger or acquisition. Should such an event occur, LendUp will seek to require that the new combined entity follow our privacy policy with respect to personal information you have provided.

LendUp may be compelled to share personal information with law enforcement, government officials, or other third parties in the event of a subpoena, court order or similar legal procedure, or when LendUp believes in good faith that the disclosure of personal information is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss, to report suspected illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our user agreement.

LendUp will not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties in the normal course of doing business and only shares your personal information with third parties as described in this policy, unless we implement a policy change and inform you of such change.

#### ONLINE ADVERTISING

We may permit third party online advertising networks to collect information about your use of our website over time so that they may play or display ads that may be relevant to your interests on our site as well as on other websites or apps. Typically, the information we share is provided through cookies or similar tracking technologies, which recognize the device you are using and collect information, including hashed data, click stream information, browser type, time and date you visited the site, and other information. This information is used to display targeted ads on or through our site, or to our users or visitors to our websites on other websites or apps. We or the online advertising networks use this information to make the advertisements you see online more relevant to your interests. You may be able to “opt out” of the collection of information through cookies or other tracking technology by actively managing the settings on your browser or mobile device. Please refer to your browser’s or mobile device’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools. (To learn more about cookies, clear gifs/web beacons and related technologies, and to learn how you may be able to opt-out of interest-based advertising from many online advertising networks, you may wish to visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and/or the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)). If you access our service on your mobile device, you may not be able to control tracking technologies through settings.

#### LendUp Allows You to Control Your Account

LendUp allows you to manage your account and information on www.lendup.com. Once you log in you may update your personal information, assuming your account is in good standing. In that case, we will retain only the personal information required by law or that we deem necessary.

#### LendUp Publishes Our Privacy Policy For Everyone To See

You can always see the most updated changes to the LendUp Privacy Policy on [www.lendup.com](https://www.lendup.com/) or by contacting LendUp at [privacy@lendup.com](mailto:privacy@lendup.com). In the event we modify our privacy policy, we may contact you via email and provide you with notice of the change and a link to review the new privacy policy.

Last Updated: 04/28/2016
